# Matthew H. Gray

matthewhgray@outlook.com | www.linkedin.com/in/matthgray | www.github.com/matthgray | 615-282-4567

## **Profile**

I'm a certified scrum master with 3-years experience as QA analyst. I have analyzed diverse sets of data in different industries. My analysis has been dedicated to improving the quality of user experience and functionality of applications.

-----

# Experience

#### 2020 - present

# Data Scientist apprentice, Nashville Software School- Nashville, TN

<u>NSS</u> is dedicated to expanding the technology workforce in middle Tennessee.

- Developed shiny <u>application</u> to visualize US healthcare spending by disease
- Developed streamlit application to visualize referrals in the healthcare system

#### 2020 - present

#### Sr. QA Analyst, L3Harris- Nashville, TN

L3Harris meets our customer demands across air, land, sea, space, and cyber.

- Maintain test plans to keep historic record of software release
- Communicate defects to product owner and developers so that it's easier for them to fix it
- Analyze automation tool TestComplete for the company to ensure it's a valid investment
- Promoted to DevOps Owner to ensure work in progress is minimized for each sprint using Azure

#### 2018 - 2020

## Jr. QA Analyst, Hilton- Memphis, TN

Hilton is a multinational hospitality company.

- Launch connected room project to over 70 hotels
- Created a document that was used for over 9000 rooms as a way to guide installers on how the device was to be set up to the different TV's in guest's room
- Mined data with SQL and tableau to visualize test results from automated tests which gave stakeholder an ease of mind that the software was 'working'

## 2016 - 2017

## English Teacher, English First- Wuhan, China

English <u>First</u> is an international education company that specializes in language training.

- Created lesson plans to teach over 150 students
- Managed 15 classrooms a week
- Communicated lessons through games and interactive PowerPoints. This increased student engagement and retention of the materials in class.

# Education

#### **Technical Skills**

2021 Data Science

Nashville Software School, TN

2016 BA in Economics

Python (Streamlit application,Plotly,ML with pytorch and Tensorflow) SQL (MySQL) University of Memphis, TN

R Studio (Shiny Applications) Affinity Photo (graphics editor) Affinity Designer (vector graphics) Intermediate Mandarine